Heat. Heat. N.
[Music]
Hey. Hey. Hey.
D.
[Music]
D
hey down
going down.
Heat. Heat.
Heat.
[Music]
Heat. Heat.
Heat.
[Music]
[Applause]
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Good afternoon. Thanks for joining us.
You're watching DProgram with me, Ted R,
editorial cartoonist, CIA whistleblower
John Kuryaku over there. I'm pointing
the wrong way because on my
>> You're right. Yeah, that was right.
>> He's backwards.
Nice to see you, John. Ted, kudos on
that music.
>> Oh, well, I wish I could take credit for
it.
>> I enjoyed it.
>> I I I picked it from uh hopefully we
don't get into any copyright problems,
but these are that's YouTube's
officially sanctioned copyright. Feel
free to use it music. So, it should be
a-ok. Okay. Uh, you know,
>> as uh someone who uh
>> good stuff
>> is uh is is always into uh intellectual
property. I make my living on it. Uh I'm
very respectful of other people's
copyright.
Um, John, we have a lot to talk about,
so we should probably dive right in.
We've France uh, as we talked about and
we anticipated has decided to uh,
formally recognize Palestine as an
independent state, exchange ambassadors,
the whole thing. We're get into, we're
going to get into that and all the
political ramifications. Uh, we've got
to talk about the uh, Democrats who are
uh, raising the alarm about the masked
ICE agents in their unmarked vehicles.
Um, they're going to try to see if they
can conduct some oversight from the
minority side of the aisle. I'm not sure
if they're going to get anywhere with
that.
>> Good luck.
>> Gain Maxwell's lawyer says she didn't
take the fifth on anything. Uh, that she
answered every question um,
fulsomely and wholly and uh, honestly.
Um, she seems to be jonesing for a
pardon. But like the cartoon of the fat
lady raiding the refrigerator, she might
be looking for love in all the wrong
places here. Um Trump uh wants to
basically signed an executive order uh
making it illegal to be homeless.
>> Yeah.
>> How do you like that?
>> Well, I I wish he could make all sorts
of things illegal. I you know, I've
already I'm already working on a cartoon
about this. Um you know, he can do an
executive order for everything. Um
anyway, so uh we will talk about the
ramifications of that. So let's get into
it. Um French President Emanuel Mcron um
had a conference next scheduled for next
week that was supposed to be concerning
the Israel Palestine crisis. Uh, and it
basically fell apart. And it looks like
he decided to um sort of take it to turn
um a lemon into lemonade and basically
pull the trigger on something that he's
been toying with for a long time, which
is to join the ranks of the many
countries like uh Spain, um Ireland,
Russia, China, Saudi Arabia, many
others, and most of the world that have
already formally recognized um the uh
the pal the Republic of Palestine. Um,
I've been arguing, John, with my friends
that this is a big deal and that huge
we're going to look back and say this
was a turning point for the people of
Palestine that uh it's hard to really uh
overstate. Um the you know and I think
that comes down to the fact that France
used to be until very recently was the
most important diplomatic country. All
diplomats had to learn be fluent in
French. French,
>> which other no matter what country they
were from, Franca, until maybe the 1920s
or 30s, you weren't really considered an
educated American if you weren't fluent
in French.
>> That's right.
>> And so it's like now my friend Scott
Stantis says, well, was is the key word.
And it's a point, you know, he's he he
it's true that maybe, but I don't think
France can be ignored. I think much of
the world when it comes to diplomacy is
going to be looking to France. I think
so too. And among European countries and
especially European Union countries,
France is a major leader along with the
Germans.
>> The Germans have thrown their lot in
with the Israelis. The French are
showing real leadership here. I think
you're right, Ted, that we're going to
look back on this decision as a turning
point. It's one thing for the Irish to
recognize Palestine, which they did back
in February, I think it was. All that
did was piss off the Israelis. But but
it it threw a bone to the Palestinians
that was really worth its weight and
gold. We we expected that to happen
because the Irish have been oppressed,
you know, throughout their history.
France though, I mean, France is one of
the historic uh colonial powers in the
Middle East. Uh that's why they speak
French in in Syria and and Lebanon, for
example.
>> Right.
>> But for the French to go out on a on a
limb like this and say enough is enough.
We're recognizing the state of
Palestine, which you're correct in
pointing out uh includes an exchange of
ambassadors
and presumably French diplomatic support
at the United Nations. Remember, France
has a Security Council veto,
>> right? I wish they could veto the
American vetos.
>> I wish they could too. This is huge. It
really is. The question now is who's
next,
>> right? That is the question, right?
Luxembourg, um,
and Italy,
>> Portugal all seem to be lining up.
>> Yes.
>> Um, there will be others.
>> There will.
>> And yeah, they're permanent. And, you
know, they're a G7 country. They're the
only uh I guess uh well, Russia and
China are on the G7. Well, no, they were
>> No, they were
>> they were um but yes, the only G7
country, so it's the only permanent
member of the security council. Yeah.
France is a colossus here. Yeah. and um
a major power in the Middle East. Um
yeah, I don't think you can overstate
this and you know um you know it's
probably the most important move of
Macron's presidency.
>> Agreed. That and his recent lawsuit
against Candace Owens, although we can
talk about that later. Now, I do want to
take note of Benj I mean, not
surprisingly, Benjamin Netanyahu was
displeased by this move, but um the way
that he expressed his displeasure on X
was particularly interesting. He
deplored the fact that uh France was
recognizing a a Palestinian state right
next to Tel Aviv.
Well, the Palestinian state was always
going to be right next to
Um, so unless he knows something about
the laws of physics or he's engaged in
ethnic ethnic cleansing,
>> ethnic cleansing because they want this
state
>> talking about
>> Yeah. They want this state to be either
on an Indonesian island or in in a a
piece of Albania that would be locked
off.
>> Right.
>> That's exactly what he's what he's
alluding to.
>> Yeah. He doesn't want it there. Yeah. I
mean, and he didn't say, you know, I
mean, if he was a temperate uh person
and leading a a normal government
instead of a gangster regime over there
in Israel, he would have said something
along that goes more like, you know, of
course, we would be the first to
recognize a lawful uh dulyeleed
democratic republic of Palestine and we
would be proud to work hand in hand to
help rebuild as neighbors and friends.
We just can't possibly work with Hamas
who have attacked us without
provocation.
That's what you would hope he would have
said. But there's no pretense here,
right? We don't. Now, he didn't say
recognize a terrorist state, recognize a
Hamas state to recognize a Palestinian
state right next to Tel Aviv.
Oh my god. You know, I remember when I
was a kid watching an episode of uh 60
Minutes in which
it was like Azer Viceman, who who was
the defense minister at the time, was
showing the 60 Minutes crew from a
helicopter
um
historical Israel, right, without the
West Bank. And at the narrowest point,
it's nine miles across from from the
line of the West Bank to the
Mediterranean Sea. 9 miles. and he says,
you know, we can't live with that. They
can cut off the nine miles and just
choke us and it would be the end of
Israel. So, we have to have the West
Bank. And even as a teenager, I was
like, are you guys out of your minds?
>> They want layman stra.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> I mean, it's so much it's amazing how
much they sound like the Germans. I
mean, it really is.
>> I mean,
>> yeah. You know, it's kind of like, you
know, I've had pro-Zionist friends
criticize me for that and making that
comparison. I'm like, well, if the jack
boot fits, wear it. You know, I mean,
>> Hunt Eli makes a good comment here, Ted.
We should probably address it,
especially the the last sentence there.
The world isn't always going to prop up
Israel. And I think that's what we're
seeing the beginning of right now. These
are the first cracks,
right? the first cracks in global or at
least western support for Israel. You're
right, the United States will try. The
United States is going to be the last
country to support an independent
Palestine, the last one.
>> But this is the beginning of it. And and
like Ted said at the very beginning of
the show, I I don't think we can
overestimate the importance here.
>> Yeah, I think I I think uh Hans Eli is
right. I think you're right. Um, and you
know, in terms of the I I agree with
Hans's question here, the first part of
it as well, isn't the Israelis
unwillingness to go along with the
two-state solution and trying to go for
the whole shmear?
>> Yeah.
>> They're unwilling to have any kind of
state solution.
>> Yeah. No, they don't want they they like
they like the current state of affairs.
>> They do.
>> And uh they and yeah, it will lead to a
one-state Palestinian solution. Um, you
know, Israel was I mean, it's funny.
Israel, I would say, I I've often
thought, was like a uh an outdated,
obsolete solution to a non-existence
problem. Now, uh but maybe it made sense
in 1948. I actually don't think it made
sense in 1948. I mean, in 1948,
you know, the the Brits were withdrawing
from the Raj, from India, the most
important colony they had. That's right.
And within 20 years pretty much every
major European power was out of Africa
or on their way out of Africa. Um and so
I mean basically the colonial experiment
that this really was I mean this really
is the goes back to 1920 and the and it
goes back before but it goes really as a
colonial experiment to the Balffor
Declaration of 1920 which was a British
colonial adventure at the peak of
colonialism but by the time it got done
colonialism was out of fashion and was
and done
>> and like and here we are. It's the last
I mean you could argue that Puerto Rico
is a colony or or or Guam, but I mean
this is the last settler colonialist
experiment. Puerto Rico is not a a
settler colonial experiment. It's the
locals who live there. We just govern
them.
>> That's I'm not saying it's right or
wrong.
>> Yeah. Right. Right. And actually even
even the Puerto Ricans are split. You
know, a third a third a third. Uh, a
third want to be a state, a third want
to be an independent country, and a
third want to leave things just the way
they are.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And I did, and I'm glad Lulu
brought this up because I was about to
mention it also, which is that Israel is
the last country to support apartheid
era South Africa.
>> Yes,
>> man. They, you know, they know how to
pick them. It's like apartheid era South
Africa and we're going to be their last
friends. I mean, yeah, we are going to
be their last friends. It's going to be
sooner rather than later. Um, it's going
to be really hard uh to for each
European country to domestically the the
the domestic unpopularity of the state
of Israel is just going to blow away.
John, I got to ask you about these
horrific photos that have surfaced in
the last 48 hours of of tiny children
>> um who have become tinier due to famine
who have been reduced to skeletons. It
reminded me of the famous footage from
Ethiopia during the famine half a
century ago when I was a kid.
>> Um, Somalia, places like that. Um, you
know, I mean, so in those situ I mean,
you could argue that all famines are
man-made. Irish potato famine, um, etc.
But this is the most man-made famine
outside of the of the Warsaw ghetto that
we've seen in a long time. I mean, five
miles away from all where this these
people are where surgeons are are
collapsing because they themselves are
starving to death and BBC journalists
are starving to death and dying. Um, now
people are, you know, eating couscous
and and hummus and
>> Yeah.
>> and drinking, you know, sweet red wine.
>> That's right.
>> This is I mean, there's plenty of food.
There's no shortage of food.
>> I said that earlier today in an
interview. There's there's plenty of
food. We see these pictures of children
starving to death. We're seeing reports
of surgeons in the middle of performing
surgery, passing out and fainting from a
lack of food. There's plenty of food.
>> The Israelis just won't allow the food
in. And when they do allow the food in
and people mob the distribution centers,
the Israelis then just open fire on the
crowds, which they've done at least
three times in the last two or three
weeks.
>> Oh, more more. It's almost every day,
John. Sickening
>> and and it's like and so I mean so you
know
>> Well, let me interrupt you for a second.
Here's a good here's a good point. I was
talking about this for with a friend of
mine, Bruard define. Sorry, I don't
speak French. What about the Egyptians?
The Egyptians are under real pressure
today to open the border. They have said
that they're not opening the border
under any circumstances.
>> If they open the border, they will be
complicit with the ethnic cleansing.
Exactly.
>> Iraq in a hard place.
>> They are. Do you just let people starve
or do you jump in on the side of the
Israelis in cleansing Gaza?
>> [__] Israelis. That's what they that
they did this on purpose.
>> Yeah, they did.
>> And and the and the and the Egyptians
aren't stupid. That's why they built
that burm over a year ago.
>> That's right.
>> Something like they're worried that the
Israelis will throw open the border and
then, you know, they won't be able to to
resist. their troops aren't going to
aren't are not going to want to and will
not shoot two million people.
>> For the last couple of years, I've
donated money to a Palestinian medical
relief organization. Not a not a lot of
money. If I have an extra 50 bucks, I
send it in. And um and I got an
automated email from them um telling
people to stop donating because there
are no hospitals in Gaza now,
>> right? There's nothing to donate to.
>> There's nothing to donate to.
Yeah, this reminds me a lot of um so
like from 1996 to 2001 when the Taliban
were uh running Afghanistan the first
time they um there were there were
Clinton administration trade sanctions
against the Taliban in Afghanistan. But
they always said no no no it's not
medical supplies or food. We don't
prohibit that at all. And when I was
there the first time in 2000 and I
visited a hospital, um, and the doctors,
and I found this to be true at other
hospitals, too. They were like, "We
haven't seen a band-aid since the early
90s." Um, and it's like nothing. Nothing
at all. It's like it's field medicine.
They It's basically like you're outside
>> a mash unit,
>> but you're inside. Yeah. That's That's
it. You have a roof that may or may not
leak. That's That's what you've got.
It's a It's a nice tent, basically. Um
>> Oh my god. So, so but John about these
pictures um you know I think you and I
are about you know we're experienced
we've seen a lot of [__] we many of us
here who are watching and reading have
too but these these pictures landed hard
with me in a surprising way and you know
pictures thousand words all that it
could really I mean I I get the
impression this is gonna
>> things
>> it makes a difference I think Macron saw
those photos and was like, "This is it.
Done." He was already on the way. And I
think that's and I think that's it. I
mean, it's just like no one wants, no
one cares anymore, but October 7th, you
know, but the Holocaust, no one cares
anymore. It's like you're out of you
guys are out of excuses. You have to
stop. Mhm. Ted, um,
I have a friend,
we've been friends for 20 years, and he
posted on Facebook. He he's not just
Zionist. He's a dual USIsraeli national.
And uh, he posted on Facebook yesterday,
this happened in the last 24 hours.
roads Greece. Israelis blocked from from
uh coming off a cruise ship. Cedos
Greece, Israelis targeted by angry
Greeks. Cyprus, Israelis had tomatoes
thrown at them. And it was like 10
things.
>> The Gazins would love to have some
tomatoes thrown.
>> I took a picture of a child starving to
death in her mother's arms. Nothing but
skin and and bone. and he blocked me.
>> That's what we're up against here. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Well,
>> yeah. They don't care if children are
starving to death. They don't care.
>> They don't. And you know what's funny?
Getting back that I'm still haunted by
that Brett Stevens column from a couple
of days ago.
>> Yeah. Day before yesterday. And and you
know in there he talked about like well
you know yes there some people who say
it's a genocide point to the genocidal
comments that were made by his
highranking Israeli officials in the
days after October 7th. But they were
just being in tempmperate. They were
being spicy. They were just angry about
October 7th. Okay. So if that had if
that were true and that was not the
official policy of the Israeli
government, which we know it is because
all the journalists have reported that
it is. But let's just say that, you
know, we're going to pretend here that
Brett Stevens is telling the truth.
>> Yeah.
>> Those people would have been fired.
>> Yes.
>> You know, if President Kuryaku of Israel
doesn't let those people stay on like
what are you doing? That's not what
that's not who we are. Please leave.
Leave your ID at the door. That's just
not I mean that's I mean that's left
them in there.
>> And remember we're talking at uh we're
talking about Smootrich and uh Ben
Gavir.
>> They were successfully prosecuted for
felony hate crimes against Palestinians
years before ever becoming
>> ministers in the Netanyahu government.
These are very bad people. They are very
bad people and they should really be. I
mean honestly um people went to prison
at Nuremberg for less.
>> Yes, without a doubt.
>> I mean I mean hell one guy just he went
to I think they killed him, right?
Julius Striker. He just bought
newspaper.
>> Yes.
>> You know granted it was a nasty piece of
work but it was just a newspaper.
>> That's absolutely right.
So
>> yeah, I'm I'm worried about where this
uh is going in that I think a whole lot
of people are going to starve to death.
Women, children, the elderly, all
civilians, they're going to starve to
death.
>> No question. They are
>> the US. Yeah. The US is not going to put
pressure on Netanyahu. It's just not. We
know what our government is like. And
I'm not saying this is specific to
Donald Trump. The Democrats are exactly
the same way.
>> Absolutely.
>> Um, so it's not it's not going to get
better in the near term. It's just not.
>> No, I mean, look, we're in a world where
even AOC can't beed on accounted upon to
uh resist sending war funding to Israel.
I mean,
>> yeah,
>> even even just from a fiscal
conservative standpoint, you should be
able to say, you know, little birds,
we've been feeding you since 1948.
>> Time to fly the nest.
>> Yeah. Yeah, that's right.
>> Yeah, without a doubt.
>> Um, is there anything else we want to
say about this?
>> I mean, Trump says that this is
interfering with his peace efforts.
There are no peace efforts, right? I
mean, there's I mean, basically, it's
very strange. Um, there's been the two
delegations in Qatar or Qatar, whatever.
>> Yeah, we should we should add that. We
should talk about that. The US walked
out
>> yesterday. The US walked out saying that
that Hamas is not serious about hostage
releases. It's like, seriously, that's
that's what the talks are about, hostage
releases.
And and why is it that we call Israelis
held by Hamas hostages and Palestinians
held by Israel prisoners?
>> That's a good question.
>> When they haven't been charged with any
crime, they were just scooped up only
because they happen to be Palestinian,
>> right? Because Israel is a nation state
and we love them. It's sort of like why
if it's Iran, it's the regime. If it's
France, it's the government.
>> Mhm.
>> It's, you know, all this loaded
language.
>> That's right. So, there there are no
peace talks right now. We walked out.
They're on hiatus and they weren't
accomplishing anything anyway.
>> No. And you know, there was a piece in
today's times and we weren't and this is
not really on the agenda, but whatever.
Like we care. Um, Russia Ukraine and
it's brought up a good point. Yeah. that
really peace negotiations haven't really
begun in earnest. No. And that's true
about Israel and Palestine. I mean, and
basically talked about shuttle diplomacy
back during the Henry Kissinger era and
whatever whatever many bad things you
want to say about Henry Kissinger. He
was uh no, you know, he certainly was a
hardworking dude. Sure. And he went back
and forth all the time.
>> Sure. Philip Habib in the 80s. Same
thing.
was a very like it was an arduous
prolonged long process to end a
complicated war between nation states.
Um you know I mean look Hamas was really
a government a real government.
>> Yes.
>> Um you know and
>> in fact the Israelis the Israelis use
the the Hamas Ministry of Health uh
numbers.
>> Yes. They accept the the Hamas numbers
on people killed or wounded or whatever.
>> Yeah. It's only the Zionists in the
United States who pretend like they're
not true. I know you can't trust them.
They're they're right. They're an
undercount. Um
>> I don't either.
>> Um Wow. Uh yeah. No. So for sure. Um the
Israelis are sitting on top of thousands
and thousands of uncharged political
they're political prisoners is what they
got and subjected to all sorts of
humiliating treatment.
>> Um so yeah peace talks um
>> you know I mean it's we're not gonna
there's no chance because you know
Israelis the Israelis aren't serious and
people will say well what about Hamas?
Well, in any kind I say in any kind of
lopsided military conflict, most of the
burden of making peace falls on the
superior military force. Um, they're
going to have the advantage. Um, you
know, I mean, they're going to have to
make most of the concessions. Um, you
know, in terms of getting close if you
want to have a ceasefire anyway. Um, I
know people will say end of World War II
or whatever, unconditional surrender.
That war went on. I I never, you know,
never I wasn't there, but I would have
never agreed with the policy of
unconditional surrender. I think it
dragged World War II on much longer than
it needed to.
>> I think you're right.
>> And th those days are gone.
>> That's just not how how conflicts end
anymore.
>> No. Now that now you like like Saddam
Hussein, you go hide in your spider
hole. You leave weapons behind and then
an insurgency pops up. And you know,
nobody ever admits that they were
defeated. Hell, right. Trump did admit
he was defeated.
>> That's true.
>> So,
>> Tom Ford,
>> good eye.
>> How How in the world did Robin Hood know
that these were Tom Ford glasses?
>> That's
>> I never even heard of Tom Ford till I
bought these glasses.
>> I never heard of Tom Ford
>> and they were like, "Oh, they're Tom
Ford." I was like, "Okay,
>> what's the big deal about Tom Ford?"
>> I don't know, but I like them.
>> Are they pricey?
>> Uh, yeah, they kind of were. Yeah.
>> Glasses. Glasses cost ridiculous. These
were like $1,200. They don't look like
much, but
>> Yeah. Well, these were only seven 700
only,
>> but still. I mean, to me, that's a lot.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. It's absurd.
>> Um. All right. Well, so I guess we
should talk about the ICE thing. So, um,
Robert, so Democratic, uh, House
Representatives Robert Garcia and Summer
Lee
>> are, um, demanding, they wrote a letter
to Christine, the Department of Homeland
Security to demand that she provide all
the information, internal DHS memos and
policies, uh, that concern how ICE is
supposed to comport themselves, um, how
they're supposed to dress. Uh, I don't
know if there's a, you know, certain
color of mask that they're supposed to
wear. You know, white in the winter, I
don't know. Pink for the gay ice
members. I don't know. Whatever. Um, but
the they're they're trying to get all
that info. Are Does DHS have to reply?
>> No. Um, it's a that's an executive order
function. They don't have to reply. And
I'll tell you, one of the things I
learned when I was uh on Capitol Hill at
the Senate Foreign Relations Committee
is most of the time
cabinet members uh just ignore us. We
would write letters to secretary of
whatever
or assistant secretary or the FBI
director or the CI dire. They would just
ignore us.
>> And what are you gonna do? Is it worth
going to the mat over the fact that they
ignored the letter from your staff
member? No. So, yeah, I don't think
they're going to get any satisfaction
here. I'm still laughing though, Ted, at
the uh at the reporting in the LA Times
that that tow truck operators are are
following these ICE officers and towing
their cars because they always park
illegally because they think they can do
whatever they want because they're ICE.
And then as soon as they get out to do
their raids, the tow trucks tow their
cars and impound them. And after all,
it's not like they can extend any
professional courtesy to these random
unidentified people.
>> Unidentified.
>> How are we supposed to know that they're
federal law enforcement officers?
Although I mean, are I officers really
law enforcement officers?
>> Well, you know what? That's a good
question.
>> Agents,
>> they're they're not really law
enforcement officers, just like Bureau
of Prisons, prison guards are not really
law enforcement officers,
>> right? They're not. I mean, they're
they're either what's called a series
1810 or 1811. In this case, they're both
1810s, which means they're allowed to be
armed, but that doesn't necessarily mean
that,
you know, like they're not going to pull
somebody over for speeding. They're not
going to they're not going to likely not
going to disrupt, you know, the the the
a shoplifter at the Walmart if that they
happen to be in.
>> Could they? I'm not even sure.
>> I remember there was some strange
experience at the university. This was
analogous maybe a University of
Cincinnati campus policeman
>> pulled over someone on a city street for
running a stop sign and it led to a
violent um you know incident where there
was a you know that the dude shot the
motorist. Um, it was it's like one of
those like shootings of black motorists
by a white cop. And I was like, can a
University of Cincinnati, you know, rent
a cop? Really play real cop? I mean,
aren't you like Paul Mart
cop? I mean, to me, an ice person, I
mean, look, if they want to be treated
like real law enforcement officers, they
ought to wear uniforms and they ought to
show their faces and they should show
ID. I mean, as far as I'm concerned,
they're just random thugs.
>> That's it. I I have to agree. Um, you
know, somebody makes a Where did I just
see it? They went to Fletzie. Uh,
Houdini. Uh, they've gone through
Fletzie, which is the Federal Law
Enforcement Training Center. I went
through Fletzie before my CIA days. I
was a But I was an 1810. So, we did the
handgun training, but I was 100% not
considered law enforcement.
>> Oh, so you don't necessar So, going to
Flexie does not necessarily What does Do
you know what Fletsy stands for?
>> Yeah. Federal law enforcement training
center. I I had a beautiful shiny gold
badge that I kept in this beautiful
leather case. I really regretted having
to turn it in when I went to the agency.
Um and it got me out of a couple of
speeding tickets.
>> Mhm.
>> But uh I I was not considered law
enforcement. I didn't consider myself
law enforcement. And um and I would not
have tried to stop a shoplifter at
Walmart.
>> I would have said, "Well, it's not my
job. Let the next guy do it."
>> Yeah. I uh I mean it's like I mean I
think it's funny how uh ICE people are
they want our sympathy too. Um
>> I don't care doxed at all.
>> I mean
>> I told you I told you on on the morning
of January 6th
>> I think I said this like a week ago. I I
had to go up to Capitol Hill to meet
with uh Bruce Fine and we knew all hell
was going to break loose later in the
day. So, I wanted to, you know, get into
Bruce's office, sign this document, and
get the hell out. And so, um, when I
parked my car, there were all these guys
taking off their Bureau of Prisons logo
polos and putting on black shirts, and I
was like, "Shame, shame, shame. You
clowns aren't law enforcement."
>> No, not as soon as you do that.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Yeah. No, it's gross. All right. So, uh,
I guess
>> can I interrupt you,
>> please?
>> In all seriousness, what do you think
about this Candace Owens situation?
Candace Owens has been on this rant for
the last three years
where she has been saying that Emanuel
Mcronone's wife was born male
and um
she's just she even did a documentary
about it there. She has no childhood
history. No documents exist. No photos
exist. Of course, none of that's true.
>> That can't be true.
>> No, it's just not true.
>> I I literally just spent like my son
doesn't know I realized was filling out
forms and doesn't even know like where I
was born. I'm like, you don't know [__]
about your family. So, I decided as a
gift I'm going to create a giant I did a
a family tree, right? I have all this
information that I've been meaning to
put together. I started putting it
together. I got it. I went down a rabbit
hole through the French and German
government uh genealogy sites.
>> Oh, very cool.
>> Go back four or 500 years, right? We
know like if if you you know in this
country, in France, in Germany, in most
countries, like uh you know, we know
where you were born, when you were born,
when you got married, which church you
got married at, you know, who you got
married to,
>> who who baptized you, where and when you
were baptized.
>> Yeah, it happened in 1611. And so like
Yeah. in and in in France I guarantee
you that uh you know Emmanuel Mrs.
Macron is is she was a it's not a dude
looks like a lady situation.
>> No, she looks like a woman and she's
obviously clearly born a woman. So
anyway, it turns out
>> not to mention she was very cute when
she was young.
>> She was cute and has a son
>> meeting up her her husband,
>> right? And has a son. So, so
the Mcron, it turned out, through their
attorneys, approached Candace Owens a
year ago and said, "Stop doing this.
It's not true, and we're going to sue
you."
>> But she doubled down.
Nobody knew this until a couple of days
ago that she had been warned to back
off. And she doubled down. And she said
that in part she doubled down because
she became she converted to Catholicism
and her Catholic faith
demands of her that she out you know
this man who is masquerading as the
first lady of France.
And so the Mcron filed the defamation
suit. Now
>> where?
>> Yeah, that's a good question. I'm not
sure where would be better for them.
England.
>> Yeah, that would be the best.
>> I really wish I'd sued the LA Times in
England. I could have because of the
internet. And so, um, and I should have
even though, you know, would have
required me to go to England quite a
bit.
>> Um, wow. Thank you. Uh, we have a couple
of paid donations here.
>> Oh, thank you.
>> So, we should answer question. So, uh,
we'll we'll go in reverse order here.
Um, obscure
obscure orca. Yeah,
>> John was about to NATO bombing of
Yugoslavia.
>> Yeah. You know what? I was about
>> I was stationed in Athens at the time
and it was absolutely miserable not just
to be an American diplomat in Greece,
but to be an Orthodox Christian American
diplomat while the United States
government was bombing an Orthodox
Christian country that the Greeks
considered to be brothers.
Um, it was absolutely miserable to the
point where
even one of my uncles attacked me
verbally at a u at a dinner
and I could barely respond to him. He
was like, "Why the [__] did you blow up
the Yugo factory? What the [__] were you
thinking you blew up the Yugo factory?"
>> That wasn't me.
>> And I said I said Theo. And I almost
didn't want to answer him. I said they
converted it to manufactured tanks,
which was true, but the bombing of
Yugoslavia was wrong, wrong, wrong in
the first place. And we created this
this fake rump country called Kosovo
that has never otherwise existed through
the course of of, you know, human
history. And it just so happens to be
holy ground for the Serbian Orthodox
Church. and it's where most of the
Serbian Orthodox uh monasteries are
located. And we're like, "Yeah, tough
luck. We're going to we're going to take
this land away from you. We're going to
give it to these Muslims that you've
been feuding with for the last 1500
years. And there's nothing you can do
about it. Oh, and by the way, we're
going to bomb you, too, just for the
hell of it."
>> Of course. I mean, obviously I have to I
agree with you, but you know what about
the argument that this was to try to
stop the genocide this the genocide uh
you know in Kosovo.
>> Yeah. Well, that that is what it was
for. Yeah. Well, less so the genocide in
Kosovo than what was happening Well, no,
it was it was Kosovo by then. Yeah.
Yeah. You know what we should have done?
>> It was supposed to create like an a
safety zone, right?
>> Yeah.
But but nobody ever said anything about
it being an independent country 5
minutes later. And I don't know and and
I I had access to the information at the
time, but it just there was no
information. Why did we not work with
Boris Yelton to figure this out? Why
were we at odds with the Russians over
this is the the the nater of our of our
relationship with the Russians? Why
didn't we do something to to make it
better?
>> Yeah. I mean, I mean, we installed
Yeltson basically.
>> We did. We did. We installed Yeltson.
>> Yeah. I mean, the Russians will never
forgive us.
>> No. And Ted, coming back to, you know,
serving in Athens in in 99 while we're
bombing uh Yugoslavia.
Every year we have to vacate the embassy
on the 17th of November because it's the
it's the date of the uprising against
the military ha that we installed. And
there's a massive demonstration
that marches from the polytenic
university where where the uprising
began to the American embassy.
So we just shut the whole place down at
12 and everybody goes home. You just get
a half a day off. We evacuated the
American embassy at least a dozen times
that year because these demonstrations
were absolutely gigantic. And at the
time, this is right before the Greeks
converted to the Euro. So they had these
100 Dramma coins that are about the that
were about the size of a of an
Eisenhower silver dollar
>> and so you could fling them and they had
some heft to them. So they would take
these 100 drama coins which were worth
about a quarter 27 cents and they would
smash all the windows on the front of
the embassy and then they would fill
balloons with red paint and with
slingshots launch the red balloons at at
so the the next day the embassy is just
peppered with
>> red paint splotches and the windows are
all broken from 100 drama coins. It was
awful. It was miserable.
>> I bet. Hey, John. Uh, we got to answer
USC AR21 who donated five bucks. Thank
you.
>> Thank you, USC.
>> Uh, I don't want to put your pardon in
jeopardy, John. Uh, but what are your
guys take on South Park going after
Trump?
>> I I DVR it. It was freaking hilarious.
>> I haven't seen it yet.
>> Oh, you got to watch.
>> You got to see it. You got to see it,
Ted. Um, I I won't spoil it for you, but
you know, they the the creators of South
Park just a couple of days ago signed a
$1.5
billion
streaming agreement.
God bless them.
>> It's obviously for the high quality
animation.
>> You know, I still watch South Park. I I
will admit to you, I watch Family Guy,
Simpsons, South Park, and Bob's Burgers.
I love all the animated shows.
>> Thank you, Caleb. Also,
>> South Park. Thank you, Caleb. South Park
is by far the most cutting edge. Like
when I watch when I watch um uh Family
Guy with with one of my housemates, I
always say, "Oh my god, how can they get
away with a joke like that?" But South
Park, it's like, "Oh my god." Like, it's
shocking to me that they're able to do
what they're what they're doing now.
It's all for a good laugh. It's all
comedy, but I I just love it. I think
it's great.
Yeah. Well, I'm Yeah. My favorite um the
thing that those two guys did that I
love the best is still Team America
World Police. I can never get over how
I've seen it more times than I could
count. It's one of the funniest I've
seen in my life.
>> Absolutely hilarious.
>> Yeah.
>> I wish I could be creative like that. I
don't think I can be creative like that.
>> See, I think I could. Uh and I think I
do.
>> Well, you I could be I wish I was in the
writer room, you know.
>> Yeah. and and you deal in in very um
sharp comedy. I mean, you're a political
cartoonist. You have to have that kind
of biting sense of humor.
>> Yeah. Well,
>> yeah, they are geniuses.
>> You would totally think. Uh but so many
of my colleagues are just uh you know,
they're wussies. Um it's because they
worked at Daily Papers and they were
scared and they were you know, I'll
never forget I got a job interview at
the Aspbury Park Press. He's dead now,
so I'll name him. executive editor Ray
Olworth brings me into his office and
you know it's like one of those things
where you really feel like it's going
well and see I'm there for a good hour.
I'm feeling like ah this I'm going to
get this. And it should be pointed out
that I've been drawing for them local
cartoons for central New Jersey for a
year. So it wasn't like I was just
blowing off blowing in off the street.
Yeah. Like we've been dating now are you
going to put a ring on it or not? And so
everything's going great. And then Rey
goes, leans back, points out the window,
and says, "There's just one more thing.
Am I ever going to look outside that
window and see people protesting because
of one of the cartoons you drew?" And I
said, I was I was flumxed.
>> I hope so.
>> I said, I mean, I was honest. I said,
it's not my intent, you know, when I sit
down to to make that happen, but I don't
care if it does. and like and people are
going to do what they're going to do.
>> Legit answer.
>> And people get mad at stuff that I never
see coming and other stuff that I think
is going to blow up the world. There's
no reaction. I I don't know. It's like,
don't you have security? I mean, I don't
know.
So, I was like I that you that look like
wrong answer tilt and you know, never
got the job. And I had one interview
like now they're like that after that.
St. Louis Post Dispatch, same thing.
Sacramento be I'll never forget the guy
he goes he goes uh
>> thank you Gav
>> Howard Weaver he goes um am I you know
what I have to figure out here is if
we're going to let the good burgers of
Sacramento wake up to ground glass every
morning on their opinion page in other
words if he hires me I'm like I hope so
uh you know that's that's what it's for.
Uh, so yeah, I mean I could this could
go we could do a whole whole show on
that, but that's Yeah,
>> I've actually purchased their
>> [__]
>> I I purchased years ago their uh Mormons
episode that people are talking about in
the chat and I also purchased the um the
lice episode. You remember the lice
episode?
>> Yes.
>> Oh my god, so funny. I still laugh out
loud every time I watch it.
>> Oh my heavens. You know, I mean, it's
like one of my I mean, I have to say if
the animation were better, I would have
seen every episode. The animation's a
little rough.
>> It's terrible.
>> Yeah.
>> But I think that's part of the charm.
>> Oh, well, look, obviously. What? It's
their 27th season. I think they've kind
of got it figured out. Yeah.
>> It's just crazy.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh my god.
>> No, I'm not complaining about them. Um,
but I have every right, but I just don't
feel like it because I don't think it
would be true. All right, so let's see
what else we got to talk about here. Um,
stuff to hit. Oh, yeah. Gizlane, how do
we pronounce her name?
>> Yeah, G. Galain.
>> Galain. I can never pronounce Gain Lady
Galain Maxwell. She um she's still her
prison photos. She's still hot.
>> Oh, she looks good. So anyway, so she's
so she So John, I'm I'm a little bit
confused by this. Like, so I don't
understand. I mean, I know that
obviously the heat is on uh on the Trump
administration over Epstein. I get it.
And but now is this just window
dressing? Are they just pretending to
look into it? I mean, it looks like she
requested the interview with the DOJ and
Dave complied and went in, had a wide
ranging conversation with her about
anything and everything. According to
>> She answered everything.
>> She answered everything. She seems like
some she could be per if she committed
perjury, she would be um she would have
exposure to prosecution. Yes. And could
extend her.
>> It it was very risky to to answer these
questions.
>> To me, that indicates someone who's
probably telling the truth. Yes.
>> When you take a risk, it's uh sort of
like when you sue for defamation, then
that's right. Subject yourself to
discovery and everything. Um
>> so what so what is this about? Like why
did this interview take place and what
was the desired outcome from both sides
and what's what's the actual outcome?
>> Well, we we this has to be speculation
because we really don't know.
>> Totally.
>> Thank you, Houdini, very much. And I I
I'm thinking that do you remember last
week, Ted, when we were talking about
the comment that that um the attorney
general made about the the videos being
just child porn and they will never see
the light of day. Pam Bondi said, "We
will never release." And I said, "We
don't want to see the child porn. We
want to know the names of the men
committing crimes against children.
That's what we want to know."
Um,
so
it could be that it could be that that
she's naming people who would be on uh
those hard drives.
>> Apparently that happened.
>> Yeah. Um
>> reportedly according to her council,
>> much of the uh
much of the uh reporting has been on,
you know, these allegations and they're
not a stretch by any means that she
wants a some sort of a commutation, even
a pardon. And Trump being Trump, um
wouldn't rule it out.
>> Well, why would he give it to her,
right? Doesn't he want her to shut up?
I can't I my brain can't wrap itself
around
what in the world would possess Donald
Trump to to throw her a bone.
>> Yeah. I mean, wouldn't he get wouldn't
he wouldn't he pardon her for being
quiet,
>> right?
>> You know, I mean,
>> not blabbing everything. And it turns
out that, you know, remember we were
joking the other day about it depends on
what your definition of a list is.
>> Well, apparently we were right about
that. And it turns out that some of the
names that are popping up are Bill
Clinton and John Kerry and a handful of
other people who are well known to every
single American. But the question
remains, who were the guys committing
crimes against children,
>> right? Like I mean, yeah. So this remind
So in the Mayflower Madam pro, you know,
>> oh yeah, I remember that case.
>> Oh, you're going back now.
>> Very old ' 80s. There was a very famous
little black book that belonged to her
that that made its way unlike the
Epstein files into the public eye. And
um and the thing is what was notable is
of course yeah she had her John's in
there and she had her girls in there but
she had a dry cleaner in there and she
had her Chinese food in there. I mean,
the point is that's what people do,
right? And and anyway, there so there's
we it's not I guess if like
>> you're looking for a spreadsheet that
says
>> my child sex client
XLS, it's not in there. Okay. But that's
not really the issue. I mean, it's kind
of like as usual, the Trump
administration is playing Well, like all
administrations, they're being they're
playing it too cute.
>> Yeah. Yeah, they are. That's right.
So, was was Maxwell railroaded?
>> Oh, I don't think so. I think she was
she was guilty. I think that there were
a whole bunch of people who were guilty.
They shouldn't have gone after just her
and Epstein,
but uh but yeah, I think she got what
she deserved.
>> Okay, so she got what she deserved. I
mean, okay, she got what she deserved.
She procured for Epstein. We know that.
Now the question is basically what this
looks like to me is they partied a lot.
Um they they probably they had lots of
young girls around.
>> They passed them around,
>> right? It's not about necessarily a
honeypot operation. It's not about msad
necessarily or probably
>> it's probably just like gross dudes
drinking and doing drugs and having a
good time. Yep.
>> And doing [__] that's illegal and
immoral sometimes. Yes. Not all. Some of
them. It's sort of like you're at a
party and there's something going on in
another room and maybe you don't go into
that other room and maybe you do go into
that other room. I think that's what it
was like.
>> I think that's I think you've hit it on
the head. You know, there's another
thing too and this is a minor point, but
it's something that I've often wondered
about. I've spoken publicly a lot about
how pedophiles are almost always locked
up in low security prisons. They're not
eligible for minimums because they're
pedophiles, which means they're dangers
to society, but they don't go to mediums
or maximums because they'll be attacked
or killed or beaten or tortured or
whatever.
>> People who are already there.
>> That's right. She's at a minimum
security work camp. How the heck did
that happen?
Why were the rules waved for her? Why is
she getting special treatment?
>> And what's your answer to that question,
John?
>> I don't know. I I don't have an answer.
>> It doesn't make any sense to me.
>> Yeah. I mean, that's the whole thing,
right? Like there may not be a
conspiracy, but when things don't make
sense, people fill in the blanks. And I
mean, and it look in all fairness,
there's weird [__] that happens in the
real world. I mean,
>> yeah,
>> you know, I mean, how the Concord
crashed is very strange. Um, right.
>> Not a conspiracy, just a piece of metal
fell off a plane that was in front of it
and went to the engine and blew it up
and now we can't fly supersonic
transport anymore.
>> Michael Gardner says, "Rich people get
different rules, even in prison."
Absolutely true. Listen to this.
There was a guy in the next row of cells
over from me. Oh, I can't remember his
name, but he was a quarterback for the
New York Giants in the early 1970s.
And he was a uh he was in for like 25
years uh for running this major massive
Ponzi scheme.
And you know, let's say he made a
hundred million and they made him pay 50
million in restitution. He still had 50
million left over. So what this guy did,
he was a real scumbag, too. What this
guy did was he paid off all the the
Mexican and black gangs to ensure his
safety, right? So he he, you know, paid
like $500 a month, I think, is what he
told me. Like 500 a month to the MS13
shot collar, 500 to the Crips, 500 to
the Bloods, 500 to the Mexican Mafia.
And then he he hated the food in the
cafeteria. Everybody did.
>> But but he hired one of the Hispanics to
be his personal chef.
And so other guys, their their side
hustle in prison is they steal food out
of the cafeteria and they're allowed to
steal food. The the guards look the
other way. So he would spend his 500 a
month in the commissary that he was
allowed to spend and then he would buy
the rest of it on the on the black
market stolen from the cafeteria. And he
had this personal chef make him three
meals a day. So you're right, Michael
Gardner. Rich people,
>> it's good to be king.
>> Yeah, it's good to be king. Rich people
are different. There are different rules
even in prison. I
>> wonder how it was for Martha Stewart.
>> Oh, everybody loved Martha Stewart.
Yeah, she taught them how to make soap
and she taught them how to make little
handy crafts. And
you know, I I think Martha Stewart's
experience in prison was kind of like
mine where I'm still in touch with a lot
of the Italians. I I spoke to two of
them last night. We did a little Zoom
call to say hi. Um
there was a there was a crooked
congressman from Ohio who went to prison
a couple years before I did. He was in
my prison.
>> Oh, I remember that guy.
>> Remember him?
>> Trafficant. No, no, this was after this
was actually the the district
immediately south of Jim Travocant.
>> Okay. All right.
>> I forget his name now, but anyway, he
said when he got out, he was in for like
two years or two and a half years. It
was a corruption charge. And he said,
"Oh my god, Clyde Hall." Yes, it was
Clyde Hall.
How in the world did you pull that up?
>> Must be an Ohio.
>> Wow. Wow. I'm Listen, man. RS. I'm
impressed. Yes, it was Clyde Hall. I
have not thought of that name in a
decade.
So, um, he got out of prison and he
said, you know, they say that, uh, you
don't go to prison to make friends. And
he says,
>> I I came out of prison having made some
of the best friends of my life. And I
remember thinking at the time, this is
before I was ever in trouble, thinking
that he was nuts.
>> But he's not nuts. And I understand it
now. Is it trauma bonding?
>> In part it could be, but but the the
people that you trauma bond with, you
tend to walk away from.
These guys were genuinely good guys. I
mean, some of them did some very bad
things. Like I remember one of them
saying I said, "So, what are you in here
for?" And he goes like this. He goes,
"The cops
found a body in a barrel in my storage
unit.
I don't know how that body got in there.
I said, "No, no." I said, "I'm not
judging you."
>> Seriously,
>> happened to anybody.
>> He goes, "A 100 people had access to
that storage unit." I said, "I'm not
judging you. Don't worry, but uh yeah,
we're still in we're still in touch."
And um it's a strange place. Um how do
people get so jacked like bodybuilders?
That's a good question. And
I saw there are three three guys that
pop into my head immediately as like the
most perfect human specimens I've ever
seen in my life because there is
literally nothing to do but work out.
Nothing.
>> What about you?
>> I I walked I made sure to walk five
miles a day around the track and when it
snows they close the track and you're
only allowed to walk around the
basketball court. So you walk around 500
times. You know, when I first arrived,
um I was walking around with with a
captain from the Banano family. So this
is a very senior guy. And it was the
first really great advice anybody had
given me in prison. I had been there
about two or three weeks. And we're walk
it's it's pouring down snow. It's like
10° and we're walking around the outside
basketball court. And he he said to me,
"How much time did you get?" I said, "30
months feels like 30 years." And he
said, "Let me give you some advice."
He said, "If somebody asks you how much
time you have, you say five years." I
said, "Why?"
>> He said, "There are guys in here with
20, 25, 30 years. If they hear that you
have 30 months and you're pissed off
about it, they're going to kick your
ass.
So, tell them five years." Does anybody
ever ask to see your paperwork?
>> Only when
>> to find out if you're a child molester
or whatever.
>> Only when you first arrived to see if
you're a child molester.
So I had to give my paperwork to the to
the shot caller for the Aryans. And um
and he he read the paperwork and he goes
intelligence Identities Protection Act.
He goes, "What the [__] is that?"
And I said, "It's like it's like
a conspiracy charge."
And he goes, "Okay."
So I sat with the Aryans for a while
till the Italians took me.
>> Yeah.
>> At at meals.
>> Yeah. There are some guys who like will
just sit with the Aryans and then the
shot caller will go up and say, "Who the
[__] are you?" and give me your
paperwork. And then the smart ones will
just go sit with the pedophiles without
saying anything.
>> Some will just claim that they can't
find their paperwork or they'll have
their lawyer write a letter. It's like,
no, no, no. If you have any idea what's
good for you, you're going to get up and
move to the pedophile table right now.
And they always do.
>> Wow. Uh I mean, I think this is I have
have to put this question up. How bad
are the showers? We've all seen the
movies.
>> Yes. You know what? That was one of the
very few questions I asked my attorneys.
One of the things that my attorneys did
for me was they scheduled a lunch a
couple of weeks before I left for prison
with a former professor from George
Washington University who played fast
and loose with the National Science
Foundation credit card and got two
years. So the very first question I
asked him was, "What's the situation
with the showers?"
And he said, "Oh no, don't worry about
that." He said, "It's nothing like what
you see on TV. You're going to go to a
low or a minimum, and they're all
individual showers, completely enclosed
with shower curtains. Same with the
toilets. They're all individual toilets
with shower curtains. Don't worry about
it at all." And he was exactly right.
And and I'll say, you know, one thing,
um, I never saw a guy naked in prison.
Well, that's not true. We we did have
one strip search once. Um, but you do
not walk around exposing yourself unless
you want to have like every bone in your
face broken.
There was a there was a an Afghan child
molester who uh came into my cell just
before I I left. I have an entire
chapter about him in my second book. And
um he went out to play soccer one day
and then he came back and we we had
these huge fans like a 4-ft tall fan
because there's no air conditioning in
prisons. And so the fan was on like for
months at a time in the summer. So this
guy went out to play soccer and he came
back and he takes off all of his
clothes. His his his clothes are
literally dripping sweat. It was
disgusting. And he goes up to the fan
and he's airing out his balls.
And I walked past him and I said,
"Sheir, you're going to get your ass
kicked. You can't." I said, "This isn't
a [__] country club. You're in
prison."
>> And he's like, "Fuck you. I don't answer
to you." Four guys were on him like
white on rice. They left him in a bloody
pulp on the floor.
>> Not surprised at all.
>> Told you. [__]
>> And he's like lifting up his balls and
airing them out. We're like, "What are
you doing? Are you out of your mind?
>> People I mean it's always weird to me
when people are in situations like this
and they just don't know how to act. Um
I have I like this question where
criminals actually respected if child
molesters chomos are at the bottom
>> who's on top or does it work that way?
>> Oh yeah. Yeah. Very much works that way.
The chumos are at the very very bottom.
The rats are very barely above the
chumos. The Italians were at the very
top. very very top and you know it was
funny because of all the gangs and
they're considered a gang
>> mafiosos or Italians or is there a
differentiation?
>> Oh there there's a there's a difference
you have to be connected in some way
>> like they'll it they'll
the Italian network is very strong and
so they'll know weeks in advance that
you're coming to the prison.
>> Um
so
>> this is also an important
>> that's a good question. Okay that's a
good question.
changed during and after your
imprisonment.
>> I assume your prison was like the
California system that I've read about
where everything is racially segregated.
>> Absolutely. Everything. You in fact at
higher levels you cannot
have any contact with other races
because you're then branded a race
trader and then you
>> you're not friends with say a Latino
just to be like
>> absolutely not can't play cards. I I
made a conscious decision when I first
arrived and I say that in my in my book.
I made a conscious decision to ignore
those racial divisions. And at the end
of my my sentence, the black shot
caller, a guy named Ali from Newark, he
was at the tail end of a 25-year
uh drug charge. He came over to hug me
and to tell me how much he respected me.
I helped him. I I wrote his resume for
him. I helped.
>> How would that happen if you weren't
allowed to?
>> Because I refused to respect those
racial divisions.
>> So you were Did you Did you get any any
[__] for that from whites?
>> No, I got [__] from the Hispanics.
And I was like, you guys all hate each
other. like the Mexicans hate the the
the Puerto Ricans and the Puerto Ricans
hate the the Dominicans and the
Dominicans hate the Costa Ricans. It's
ridiculous. I like you guys all look
exactly the same to me and you all hate
each other. I just never understood it.
Um so the Italians were by far the most
respected and that was the point I was
going to make of the gangs, right? If
you're if you're in an organized gang,
MS-13, Bloods, Crips, Mexican Mafia,
Burachos, Nortenos, all these guys, your
prisoner number ends with the number
-47.
47 means organized gang. Well, the
Italians were also 47s.
Um, so of all the gangs, the Italians
were by far the smallest and by far the
most highly respected.
And what about what? And was there a
charge that was most respected like
>> like like you know like in the hierarchy
of robbery, murder?
>> Rico. Rico.
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah. Rico. And Rico usually had murder
attached to it. Usually it was
conspiracy to commit murder because you
know a guy will murder somebody and then
20 people will get charged for it
because they're all part of the
conspiracy.
>> I'll tell you who who they didn't like.
They didn't like these these big rich
white collar criminals.
>> Really?
>> Yeah. Yeah. They didn't like those guys.
The only ones who, you know,
>> were they just viewed as soft and uh
>> Yeah. soft. Oh, you thought you're going
to get away with it. Oh, poor you. You
got caught and now it's like, "Oh, I'm
in prison. Oh my god."
>> So, so it's a class thing. It's class.
>> It's a class thing. The only The only
guys who were in where nobody gave a
[__] was like arson. I knew three
arsonists and people people were like,
"Eh, arson. Did you kill anybody?" No.
Okay, nobody cares. Like insurance
fraud, mortgage fraud. Uh, one guy was
property fraud, which I had never heard
of before.
>> Funny, he he just forged papers um
transferring ownership of a golf course
to himself
and then he tried to charge people rent.
>> He's like one of those squatters with
the that write up the fake deed.
Exactly. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> It's kind of a big deal, right? It's
sort of like how car theft is uh, you
know, is is is a direct hair to horse
theft and it's cons and you're basically
stealing a a man's livelihood. So, it's
considered
>> Yeah. not cool,
>> really serious. And stealing a man's
home is the same way. Um, this question
from Nick. Um, what are our thoughts
about all the recent trade deals? the
tra, you know, I I told my sister this
the other day. I can't believe Trump is
actually getting away with it.
>> I know.
>> People were saying, "Oh my god, he's
nuts and the tariffs 100% and 50%. Oh my
god, he's coming to deals with all these
countries and they're deals that favor
the United States." I can't believe I'm
saying it.
>> So, yeah. No, I I I I don't have
anything to add to that. That's that's
very very very true. Um, all right. So,
finally, um, but maybe not least, um,
Donald Trump issued an executive order,
uh, stating that he's, uh, very upset
about the the explosion of homelessness.
>> Yeah.
>> The executive order actually understates
the problem. It says that there's
250,000 homeless people in the United
States. They're actually 770,000.
>> I was going to say by a factor of three
or four. Yeah.
>> And and it's gone up a lot. That number
was 550 for years and then it shot up um
over really over the last four years
since since COVID and prices shot up and
uh people got priced out of housing.
That's not counting the millions who are
couch surfing
hidden hidden homeless. But he's he
doesn't care about that. He he said it's
a bad look in DC for foreign dignitaries
to see tent cities as they drive in from
Reagan airport. He's right. Um he he
says that it's uh you know it's it's
it's disturbing and dangerous for
law-abiding citizens to see people
pissing and shooting outside.
>> Yeah. Nobody wants to see that. But
>> you know
>> that's capitalism for you.
>> That's capitalism and you can't keep
cutting the budget and starting with
with services,
>> right? So, so, so here's what he So,
Donald Trump, I think, is really good at
diagnosing problems like, hey, factories
in the Midwest have closed and we
haven't retrained anyone and everybody's
just depressed and and poor and uh
addicted to opiates.
>> Yeah,
>> that sucks.
>> for me, but he's and he's right. And and
honestly, that is not a small thing.
Being able to diagnose the problem is
very, very important. Like, I didn't see
Joe Biden doing that. I didn't see Kla
Harris doing that. Okay, good for you.
But Trump's very bad at coming up with
the um with the cure and the treatment,
right? And so here he want he's
basically the thesis here is that the
vast majority of public homeless people
are mentally ill, uh emotionally
disturbed, uh drug addicts, or some
combination thereof. That's probably
true. If they aren't before they get on
the street, they rapidly deteriorate.
I've seen that happen in my neighborhood
here in New York.
So what do we So the question is what do
we do about it? His answer seems to be
forcible commitment. Now I'm not the
kind of liberal who's going to say that
someone should has their has a moral and
legal right to sleep outside in
Manhattan when it's five below zero,
right?
>> No. No. I want them picked up,
>> dragged off and and taken somewhere. But
I want them taken somewhere safe
>> and nice and warm. I don't want them to
be abused, treated like [__]
humiliated, um attacked, raped,
whatever. So, the problem is that
there's no facilities here. So, it's a
two-part thing, right? We've got drug
addicts and we've got um mentally ill
people. And he's like basically reopen
the insane asylums like the old
Creedmore, you know, scandal from the
70s.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Where people were chained to, you know,
to their beds and stuff. Yes.
>> Well, the point is,
>> Mr. present. There are no facilities,
right? Where are you going to put them?
This reminds me of the mass
deportations. There's no facilities to
handle the mass deportations. There's no
facilities to handle the mass removal of
the homeless from American city streets.
I mean, where are you going to put them?
And and that goes double for drug
addiction. There's no treatment really
available. There's no services
available. If you want to create a
massive infrastructure, a massive safety
net to deal with these people, God bless
you and I will help you and I will
support you and I will scream it to the
heavens. What a great president you are.
But I don't see that happening.
>> No, I don't see it happening either. Um,
our our viewers are making a lot of
really good points here. First of all,
the the tent uh right behind the
executive office building. Uh there's
also another one now up at uh Union
Station. Same idea.
My guess is he'll find some pretext to
to move them out. Uh you know, Reagan,
well, it started really under Carter
where the Supreme Court ruled that
people could not be held against their
will if they were not a danger to
themselves or to others. But a lot of
them are a danger to themselves or to
others and and they're deserving of
mental health care.
>> Yes.
>> So what what do we do? Do we
>> do we make it easier to force people
into mental health care? And then on the
other side,
>> lots of abuse, right? I mean,
>> lots of abuse. had when I was a little
kid, my neighbor, he decided that it was
like a lot easier and cheaper than
paying alimony to have his wife, who was
perfectly wonderful and lovely and sane,
forcibly committed. And she spent six
months at the local Zane asylum in
Dayton before she managed to get out.
Um, that kind of [__] used to happen all
the time.
>> Yeah.
>> So, I mean, you don't want to make it
too easy,
>> but you don't want to make it too hard
either.
>> California suffered with that for many
years. many many years. And it was in
the 1970s that they finally changed the
law so that the police couldn't forcibly
commit you. Can you imagine the cops
just ring your doorbell and then by
force take you and put you in a mental
institution and there's literally
nothing you can do about it?
>> Well, I mean in in a sense in a sense
that does happen now. I don't know if
you've seen the Netflix I think it's
Netflix the movie we care a lot, but
it's
>> Oh, I have. Oh my god.
>> Real phenomenon, right?
>> Yes, it is. Like so basically um these
nursing homes they they they they
conspire to have people
>> power of attorney.
>> Yeah. And and there and and it's for
people often who've done ab who are
perfectly fine. Nothing's wrong but they
target them because they're rich and
they're going to take their money
>> and they do they take their money. Uh
but you know we we really we we spend
scandalously little money on mental
health and in fact
>> even though it's even though mental
health parity is in the Affordable Care
Act completely uninforced
>> completely uninforced and in most
counties I I read this I think at the
Rutherford Institute website um in most
counties in in America
>> forcing into mental healthare shall be
done after mental health care is vastly
improved if at all. If at all.
>> Exactly. That's right.
>> So, in most counties in America, there
are more mentally ill people in the
county jail than there are in mental
hospitals.
>> Yeah. Well, there just aren't enough
mental hospitals. And the mental
hospitals that are there suck ass.
>> Yeah.
>> So, um Yeah. I had a I had a friend her
um she discovered her ex-husband had
committed suicide. She walked in on him
>> and um and uh and found him. The guy had
almost took a butcher knife and nearly
hacked his own head off in his kitchen.
>> Oh my god.
>> Unsurprisingly, she freaks out, runs
into the streets of Brooklyn, screaming
and screaming, you know, I want to die.
NYPD shows up understandably. They think
they have a mentally distraught woman on
their hand, which they did. And uh they
so they dragged her off to uh Belleview
um and and put her in like the padded
room. She saw her phone, so she called
her sister. Her sister came to visit and
her sister was like, "Honey, I know
you're really upset." She said in a
really low voice, "But listen, they're
going to keep you here unless you can
pretend like you're okay." Like, do you
understand what I'm saying? They're
going to keep you here like
indefinitely, maybe forever. You have to
get it together. Stop crying. Stop
sobbing. And just be like, "I'm good
now. I can go home and just keep it
together and so that they'll let you go.
And she did. Um, and then she fell apart
later. But I mean, it's like that's
that's how it works.
>> There was even an episode of Lou Grant
about this. Um, I happened to see on
Hulu years ago where uh this
investigative journalist who was working
at the LA whatever it was called,
Dispatch,
um,
uh, got himself committed to a mental
hospital so he could write an article
from the inside. And
>> that's what that's what happens with the
Creedmore document.
>> Yeah, that's right. But he couldn't get
out.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Couldn't get out.
>> And they drug you. Yes.
>> So, yeah. I mean, they drug they drugged
the seniors and old folks home, too, to
make them compliant.
>> Yes.
>> And there's
so they weren't great before they showed
up and they're definitely not great
after that.
>> Um, they did it to my mom. I watched
them do it. I knew they were doing it.
And there's it was, you know, basically
when they say you need an advocate when
you're in there, they're not wrong. You
need you need to be there like all the
time. Um, I wanted to Yeah, this is a
good question actually. So, there's a
border.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Border conflict, right? Thailand and
Cambodia going on right now. It's not
like war in the Southeast Asia has ever
been a problem for the United States.
So, maybe we don't need to talk about
it.
>> Uh, but in all seriousness, um, Thailand
deployed an F-16 across the border into
Cambodia and, uh, and took out artillery
positions. They claimed that they were
retaliating. This all boils down to a
goes back to a treaty from 1907.
>> Yeah. by the French colonial power that
set that border as usual the text. So
this is fascinating as a graphic artist,
right? So the text of the treaty says
that basically the the the border
follows the natural flow of the river,
but the drawing that went with it that
some Frenchman in 1907 drew doesn't
really do that. and it puts this temple
that's uh on the Cambodian side of the
border and the Cambodians are like thank
you and everybody went everybody went
with the with the drawing and as graphic
artists I agree with that 100%. But you
know I think actually under under most
treaties you look at the words and um
and the ties are like well we're looking
at the words [__] the drawing and so
that's what this is all about. It's like
art versus text
>> crazy. And um and it's about this this
temple. Um this this seems like maybe
not a big deal, but it's not not a big
deal either.
>> Tell you the truth, I didn't even
realize that the Cambodians had a
military.
>> Oh, really?
>> Seriously? Yeah.
>> Well, it got really over Well, the Cime
Rouge got overrun by the Vietnamese.
>> Yeah,
>> that was a long time ago.
>> Yeah, sure. Sure.
>> It must not It must not be much of a
military.
>> It It can't be. And they still have all
those minds all over the place. Yeah.
When I when I first saw this, I was
like, "Wait, what?" And then I had to I
had to reread it like, "Okay." And
they're they're firing at each other
across the border, too.
>> Yeah.
>> This happens between India and China
every few years.
>> That's true. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Kind of major war over it in 192.
>> Um and then there's uh Yeah. Yeah. Like
a few years ago, right? Drunken border
guards. Uh-huh.
>> They drink a lot up there. Nothing to
do.
>> Things get out of control.
>> That's what I always say. It's like
that's why that's why Putin never wanted
a NATO country on his border. He knows
about drunken border guards.
>> Yeah, that's right.
>> And then the next thing you know, you've
got like French nukes headed your way.
>> Crazy.
>> With Article Five of NATO. Uh, we were
asked, and I'm sorry, I apologize to
whoever it was who asked this earlier in
the chat, but I I'm going to do a call
back. I hope you're still here. Um, what
do we think about Trump's reversal on
NATO? He used to hate it. Now he loves
it. Well, you know, Trump's always
flip-flopping like a fish on his dock.
>> Um, what do you think?
>> I think he really believed that Vladimir
Putin would do what he told him to do.
And I think he's just so angry that
Putin won't just go to the negotiating
table and settle this thing with Ukraine
that now he's got to embrace
NATO. He's got to otherwise he's going
to be out there all alone.
>> Well, this is like this is what we were
talking about earlier, right? I mean,
it's like diplomacy takes [__] work.
>> Exactly. I mean, Bill Clinton, I know we
neither of us supports supported his
actions in against Serbia, but I do have
to hand it to him. You know, the date I
love the story about how the Dayton
Peace Accord came to be, right? So, he
cleverly brought the three leaders of uh
Serbia, Croatia, and uh um who am I
forgetting here? Um Kosovo. Yeah.
>> To uh to Dayton uh to the Air Force
base, right? Patterson Air Force Base.
And you know, having grown up there, I
I'm pretty sure uh Bill Clinton was
aware of the fact that it was one of the
most boring places in the United States.
So he's like, "You got you got you guys
work on this, you work it all out, then
you get to go home." And anyway, so he
left them there. And they were kind of
kept prisoner.
>> Yeah. And
>> but he but he did give them soccer
balls. I remember that.
>> But he but they were getting really
desperate. And finally he was like I
tell you what there is a French
restaurant called Low Bears. It's just
south of D South Dayton. It's the only
French restaurant in Dayton.
>> You guys you fellas can all go down
there and you can have a good meal but
you got to sign you got to sign the
agreement.
>> And uh so Slabadon Malloic and the rest
they were like man I gotta have me a
good meal. Dayton sucks. So they so they
all signed and u and and like so they I
grew up like you know I don't know a
quarter of a mile from Lil Bear um and
they so I used to walk by it on my way
to on my way from my house my mom's
house to uh to my school every single
day and anyway so they they keep they
went to Loberish and and and had a nice
kind of old-fashioned too much sweet
sauce you know old style French place
it's gone now at Town and Country
Shopping Center and and They had they
used to have a seating chart like with
you know they showed like where all of
the diplomats sat.
>> That's cool.
>> And where Clinton was and all that what
what type of wine they had. But I always
always like I laughed at that. I was
like this is like French food diplomacy.
We're hungry. We can't eat this shitty
base food anymore.
>> No. No. It gets to be too much.
>> Yeah. And by the way, uh totally true.
Uh Two Toes.
>> Yeah. That's a surprisingly excellent
museum.
>> It is big. It's not like a, oh, pop in
for 30 minutes and you'll see
everything. That's a half day event and
it's good. I mean, it's also got a
strong uh aeronautics aspect to it also.
Um, and also uh and also all the the
space stuff is amazing, too.
>> Um,
>> yeah.
>> So, someone I lived in Dayton then. The
story back then is that Maloshva
insisted something needed to be signed.
I think it was Clinton, but I don't
know.
Who knows? Who knows? All we know is
that people were hungry. They ended up
at Loberge.
>> Indeed.
>> But um yeah, and it was a boring place.
Um but anyway, yeah, I love that story.
So um so let's talk a little bit before
we should wrap it up. The um the the the
the homeless executive order.
>> Yeah. Um,
this could be an opportunity for
Democrats to say, "You know what, Mr.
President, you're right. Homelessness is
a is a national shame for the world's
richest country. Um, we shouldn't have
anybody sleeping outside. Let's let's
work together on this. Um, that's that
can't happen, right?"
>> No. Yeah. There was a piece in the post
today saying that, you know, it's all
fine and good to sign an executive
order, but the the truth of the matter
is that this is a a state issue and he
might be able to to fiddle with what
little federal funding there is, but
there's nothing he can do to force, you
know, tent cities to be removed or to
force people into mental institutions or
whatever. He can't do anything. Now, if
he wants to make a proposal to take
abandoned or mothball military bases and
turn them into housing for the homeless
where maybe they can undergo some job
training, get mental health uh care,
whatever, and then be reintroduced into
society. I guess that's something else.
But I think this is mostly talk.
>> I agree. Yeah. I mean, I don't think
it's one of those things that can get
done this way. Very I think we could
maybe ask answer this last question. I
think we need to and then we should be
on our way and start our weekends. So
what do you think
>> what do we think about Trump saying
Obama could be arrested over the Russia
election scandal?
>> Well, thanks thanks to Donald Trump
going to the Supreme Court, a president
can't be arrested for anything.
>> Correct.
>> Issues issues done closed.
>> If it was ex Yeah. All that Obama would
have to argue is that he did it in the
exercise of his functions as president
of the United States.
>> Yes. Now, John Brennan is another issue.
Just before we started this show, I
interviewed um Matt Taibbe for for my
other podcast, Deep Focus, and Matt says
I I I sort of lamented the fact that
that what the Justice Department um has
had referred to it is um misdemeanor
charges against Brennan and Comey. um
related to allegedly lying to Congress.
And he said, "Yeah, that's true." But he
said what he's hearing now is that they
are actively pursuing felony conspiracy
charges against at least Brennan and
maybe Brennan and Comey.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah. And I'll tell you what I mentioned
to you offline the other day.
>> I will go to Brennan's trial every
single day.
>> I mean it
>> with a big fat grin on your face.
>> Karma is real and she's an evil [__]
>> And I think that's a perfect place to
start our weekend.
John Kuryaku, thank you so much as
always. It's a pleasure to be here with
you. That was so much fun.
>> Yeah, it's always fun. Uh we're we're
we're deprogram. We're going to be here
again next week. Monday, Wednesday,
Friday 5:00 pm Eastern. Maybe we should
try for the week the the whole every day
the week after maybe. But
>> sure, we could try that.
>> Okay. All right. So, Monday, Wednesday,
Friday, Eastern 5 o'clock. Um please
like, follow, and share the show.
Seriously, please share it. Like, you
know, just find the link and pass it
around. Massive thing for us. Um we're
trying to get it. I mean the numbers are
definitely go in the right direction but
um anything you can can do to make them
go there even faster would be much
appreciated. Um as always thanks for
your questions. It was always fun to
answer them. We have the best fe the
best viewers. Love you guys. Take care.
>> Thanks everybody.